

# Ólafur Siemsen Sigurðarson

⊠ OlafurSiemsen@protonmail.com

### **Education**

2016–2019 Bachelor, University of Iceland, Reykjavík - Iceland, Physics.

## Experience

2014–2014 Research technician, University of Iceland, Reykjavík.

I set up a server to house GPUs for scientific computation in the field of skyrmionics. The server is being actively used for computational physics (as of 2021). I remain responsible for the server's continued maintenance and improvement.

2013–2018 **Teaching Assistant**, University of Iceland, Reykjavík.

I taught the lab portions of first year physics, focusing on effective data collection and analysis with an emphasis on keeping good lab notes. Syllabus included error propagation and assessment. I also taught the tutorials for the first semester of physics (mostly Newtonian mechanics).

## Languages

Icelandic Native

English Advanced (116/120 TOEFL)

Danish Moderate German Moderate Swedish Beginner

Knowledge Area

11110 W10480 11104

Scripting

Coding/ Matlab, FORTAN, Python (including PyROOT and numba)

Media Excel, Word, Latex

#### About me

I have a deep thirst for knowledge in a wide range of subjects, from physics and mathematics to psychology, philosophy, cellular automata, artificial intelligence and linguistics. More recent interests lie in the intersection between physics and philosophy.

While I list proficiency only for those programming languages with which I have worked extensively, I have a deep understanding of underlying principles and have strong flexibility when picking up new languages. I have done some minor work in C, writing interfacing between CUDA and FORTRAN as well as sundry coursework.